The train heading from Lonpur to
Dhanbad is ready to leave...
MADHAVGARH
Did you have to
visit Bihar for a trip?
Why?
What's wrong with Bihar?
Wait...
You should ask what
is right with Bihar?
Gang wars, caste wars,
Maoists, Naxals
and God knows what else.
You didn't tell me,
where did this sudden
love for Bihar come from?
Hey, get in.
Hey! Get in!
Give me your bag!
Let's go.
Get in.
Look brother, I don't want
to be anyone's son-in-law
I am too old to get married.
I am the wrong choice for this.
I have blood pressure and diabetes,
I am telling you I am useless.
They know you are useless.
This is not a gang that abducts
people and gets them married.
Then who are they?
Why are they kidnapping us?
Just wait and you will
have your answer.
Come on. Get out.
Okay, okay.
Who is that?
Baabi.
You broke our pact Bhombol.
This is not done.
What kind of a welcome is this?
I sent a car and security.
You could thank me, you know?
What about a garland? A band?
Why do you look like a mess?
How long has it been since
your last haircut?
Excuse me. Wait a minute.
Baabi? Bhombol?
Why don't you call Mom?
If I call her all the time then she
will leave everything in my name.
Did you forget? I might be useless
but I am Mom's favourite.
You are brothers!
That is what Mom says but
I think this is a case of a rainy night
and orphanage and the father of a church.
Jayavrat this is my
brother - Mrinmoy.
Same genes...
but I think he got
all the coward genes.
-Hi, I am Jay--
-New roommate.
-Yes.
-Jayavrat.
Jayavrat Saini.
Bhombol?
Are you getting married?
An MLA's daughter
is getting married.
What are they serving in
the buffet?
Scandal. Sex scandal,
extortion, bribery,
hidden cameras, blackmail,
And dessert?
Politicians.
Now I am hungry.
In these few districts of Bihar
gang wars are a
frequent occurence.
That's not even mentioning the
caste issues and Maoist troubles.
In fact, 6 months ago there
was a huge massacre.
And now all of a sudden...
In the middle of all this...
We have an extortion
and blackmailing case...
Now my plate is full.
That is why I called you.
Get to work.
Enjoy.
See you.
Hey Shekhar...
Don't you think your brother...
Bhombol looks a bit like me?
By the way, what
does your brother do?
I can tell you
but then I will have to kill you.
Oh my.
Well, I need a drink.
The bar is very crowded I literally
had to fight for this scotch.
It's fake.
It was smuggled in from Nepal.
If you want the real thing then the
drivers are drinking Mahua outside.
Go there.
I can't believe they
gave me fake alcohol.
Impressive.
Did you know already...
or was it just guesswork?
Guessing is hardly any work.
I see.
This will be fun.
Were you invited to the wedding
or did you come for the free food?
No, I came to enjoy the clarinet.
You play a string instrument but
you came to enjoy the clarinet?
Rough fingernails...
and the corn on the right
hand because of the bow.
Good observation.
-Your good name?
-It is a very good name.
My name,by the way,
is Shekhar Home.
Shekhar Home.
Nice to meet you.
Yeah... Nice... nice...
And... what... is your name?
Iraboty!
See you later?
No... I doubt it.
I dug this out myself.
I see you're socialising.
No... just...
Are you sure you
don't want to drink?
I don't... I...
No... I don't.
You should you know.
They say alcohol
is a social lubricant.
Yes. John Kouriskey.
Not bad.
Hey, isn't that...
Iraboty. I mean, I don't know
who she is...
She is the one singing but you're the
one standing with your mouth open.
Come in.
You already know Mr. Yadav.
This is Mr. Jitendra Jha.
That is Mr. Sushil Pandey.
Honourable members of
the Bihar State Assembly.
Congratulations on your
daughter's wedding Mr. Yadav.
This is a great function.
Can we start?
Go fetch it.
Post two men outside his home
on Bailey Road, in Bidya Colony.
-Yes.
-Make them sit outside with a gun.
And if anyone causes any
trouble you shoot them dead.
-Understand?
-Yes sir.
If anyone tries to file
a complaint against me
then you should inform me.
Then I will handle where to
dispose of their bodies.
-Understand?
-Yes sir.
Where is the love letter?
Love letter...
Ransom note.
YOU MUST PAY THE PRICE
You must pay the price?
This sounds like a dialogue
from a Dharmendra movie.
'Pratigya'.
This is not a dialogue
from 'Pratigya'.
But the question still remains
the price for what?
Who was the Heroine in 'Pratigya'?
-Hema Malini.
She...
Hey! Shekhar!
Shekhar!
What happened?
Are you crazy? There are MLA's waiting
for us inside and you're chasing a girl?
Hema Malini is not
the Heroine in our film,
she is the villain.
Where have you brought
me so early in the morning?
You didn't even let me drink tea.
Hey!
Shekhar this is illegal.
It's locked. There is no one here.
Let's go.
What? Are you conducting a
structural analysis?
-What is going on here?
-Let's go soldier.
-Let's go.
-Let's go!
-Hey.
Hey Shekhar?
Let's go.
What were you even
doing in the army?
Even in the army
I was just a doctor.
Come.
Whose house are
we breaking into?
What are we doing here Shekhar?
Will you tell me something?
Oh my God!
Now I understand.
Now go look for the tapes.
There are a lot of cupboards.
But why would she hide
the proof in her own house?
It's safe, secure and accessible.
But don't ask questions.
Get on the job.
Room.
-There is nothing in that room.
-Check that one.
-That room.
-Will you stay in this room?
Shhh.
That room.
Shekhar!
Should we start the matinee show?
It looks like she is her own
biggest fan just like you,
don't you think so?
Ask her yourself.
What do you mean?
Want some tea?
I don't mind.
Don't be scared.
It's not poisoned.
Drink it before it gets cold or
it will taste like sherbet.
Did you find anything in the tapes?
Simmondsia Chinensis.
Scientific name for Jojoba.
It is a plant that
grows in deserts.
It is the fragrance you give off.
Nice to meet you.
Wow.
You didn't even give me a proper
handshake but you still know so much.
Your hands held some
secret fragrances.
Your homemade Jojoba oil.
By the way,
it's difficult to find this
oil in Bihar & Bengal
You studied in
Rajasthan, didn't you?
Your Gurukool (Music school)
was there.
What else do they teach
other than music?
Learning the ragas also
teaches you about pain.
But you have everything.
Beauty, money and fame then why
are you blackmailing the MLA's?
For power?
Even a light bulb holds power.
The problem with power is that
it can be turned off with a switch.
You don't want power...
You already have money...
So why do it?
Interesting.
Interesting! We should leave.
I am sure Iraboty has a lot
more to do than just talk to us.
Okay.
Thank you.
Sorry...
See you later.
I doubt it.
Did you notice?
As soon as I confronted her on
blackmailing the MLA's
her face went pale.
Whose phone call
was she waiting on?
Phone? What phone?
You just said you
noticed something.
Didn't you notice that she was
waiting for someone to call?
-Really?
-Really.
Then at least we can get a list of
all the people who called her today.
It has to be an opposition leader!
She likes playing the game alone.
Typical egoist.
Brash, rude...
narcissistic.
Sounds like somebody else I know.
Hey, isn't that your brother's car?
Does he bring everyone
he kidnaps to this hotel?
What do they say in English?
Cat on a...
Hot tin roof?
Baabi, we got the ransom call.
Three MLA's need to bring 20 kilos of
gold to the same place at the same time.
We should leave immediately.
20 kilos of gold?
Yes and be careful they are
carrying more guns than gold.
Let's go Shekhar.
Baabi?
What time did you
get the ransom call?
At around 9:30.
And at what time do you
need to be at the location?
10:30. Which means right now.
Which means the phone call
she was waiting for
was not for the confirmation
of the ransom call.
She?
That's right, this means she already
knew the ransom calls have been made.
She was waiting
for a different call?
I don't understand what you're
trying to say... Who is she?
And whose call?
Where is the pick-up point?
No one is coming here.
What? Why?
What is wrong?
They don't want your gold.
They just wanted to know
where you kept it.
Where did you get this gold from?
From a brick factory.
From a gas godown.
From my in-law's home.
All three of these
places were the targets.
Black money, gold,
paperwork for properties which these
politicians can't store in banks
are held in these safe-houses.
Which got vandalised.
But the MLA's still insist
that nothing is missing?
Iraboty was waiting
for the phone call
to inform her of when the MLA's
would leave their safe-houses.
But she still hasn't found
what she is looking for.
Okay, I will get Iraboty
picked up for questioning.
You won't find anything.
Why?
Even though we know
that she is the blackmailer.
On what basis will
you interrogate her?
"The fact that you own Jojoba oil is
proof that you are the blackmailer,"
will you say that to her?
-Come on Baabi.
-Come on Bhombol.
Take this.
So what exactly does she want?
There is a common connection
between all of those videos,
find it and you will
know what she wants.
Do you want to find out?
Yes, of course.
Okay then I will
head to Bailey Road
and you head to Yadav's brothel.
Why should I go to the brothel?
I am an honest man.
You go to the brothel and I
will head to Bailey Road.
Oh my, my. "Honest man?"
Oh sir! Please come in.
Tell me, Bengali, Bihari,
Punjabi, Nepali, Gujarati...
All available! There are
no charges just for looking.
No... A Bihari-Bengali will do.
-Malti...
-No, that's... one more thing...
-If she wears a gajra in her hair...
-You want a Gajra?
-Rinku!
-No, I already saw her...
I also want a bindi on
her forehead. A big one.
You want a gajra and a bindi?
And if there was a
mole on her skin...
Oh my! It looks like sir
is a connoisseur.
Gajra, bindi and a mole!
-Th... There is one more thing.
-Another? Go ahead.
I want a leather belt.
You won't get that.
Really?
So why don't you just send her?
How many times have I told
you not to step outside? Come in.
Hey! Hey! There is no need for that.
Put your clothes back on.
Yes, yes, that's fine. Sit down.
What is your name?
-Sujata.
-And what is the mole girl's name?
-You came from the MLA's office right?
-No I didn't.
What is the name of
the girl with the mole?
-Bimla.
-Where is Bimla?
I am being honest,
I don't know where he is.
Sir it's not about the money.
I really don't know.
Did she say anything
before she left?
No... she just suddenly
disappeared.
I don't know where she went.
You don't know where she went...
Do you know where she came from?
She is from Begusarai.
I have a problem Sujata.
You know how some
people have pacemakers?
I have a lie-detector in me.
You see, lying is an art.
There is sweat on your forehead,
your pupils are dilated
your fingers are trembling,
you need to control these things
before you start lying.
Tell me, where is she from?
KHORIDAI - 0 KM
The Bat said to the Porcupine
"We will see something fun tonight.
The owl will come out to hunt,
and the rat will face it's death..."
Hello Bimla.
What do you want?
I want to meet someone.
Who?
The one who is standing
outside the door.
Iraboty.
Tell her I am here to help her.
Help?
You work for the MLA's.
Your job was to capture me.
If I wanted to do that
then I would have brought
the police with me the other day.
You did not find what
you were looking for.
I know that.
I want to help you.
Go ahead, I am listening.
Khoridai...
It looks like a ghost village.
There are widows everywhere
and there are bullet
holes in the wall.
So many people died and yet the
media doesn't even know about it.
Why is that?
Iraboty,
a few months ago the people of
Khoridai protested against the MLA's
those protests turned violent.
Buses were burnt.
Gandhi bhavan was ransacked.
Highways were closed off for
two to three days.
And so, to put an
end to the protests
the MLA's brought
their thugs to Khoridai.
Bimla's husband was
killed in this massacre.
Bimla wanted revenge.
You made a plan.
Bimla went to the brothel
that Yadav visits frequently,
she became Yadav's
favourite and then...
the video.
Right?
You ran a sting operation on
the other two MLA's.
And then?
My assistant... my
partner will tell you the rest.
No, no, no...
Hello.
Hello partner.
So you got caught too?
More like got myself caught.
Anyway... what did you find out?
Once I reached
Bailey Road, Vidya Colony
I asked around
about those two thugs.
Here you go.
-Tell me something.
-Yes?
Do these two spend all day here?
Don't ask me sir.
I will get killed for no
reason just like Pankaj.
Pankaj who?
Tell me more.
He was a great man.
That is his house there.
He was a journalist for
Swatantra Dainik newspaper.
I went to the Swatantra
Dainik headquarters
and found out that he was
working on a big story.
That reporter Pankaj was here
on the day of the massacre.
He took a lot of pictures.
As soon as the MLA's found out
they started pressuring him
not to release the story...
but he didn't listen.
The MLA's did what they
always do to shut someone up.
But they still haven't found the
photos he took or their negatives.
Hey, shut up!
Look for it in the corner.
That is why they still
keep an eye on his house.
They track every
move his family makes.
Was Pankaj... your friend?
Iraboty?
And you want justice for
him and his village.
The evidence these MLA's
are looking for to destroy it.
You are looking for
the same evidence...
to show it to the world.
But neither you nor they
have found that evidence.
You will release those
video tapes through the media...
so that, even if you
don't get justice
at least their names
will be tarnished.
I don't want their names tarnished
I want them punished.
They will just claim
that this is not them.
It's a doctored tape.
The truth will be revealed
once an investigation starts.
If there even is an investigation.
When was the last time
you spoke to Pankaj?
On the day of the protest.
He was scared.
He said he has proof
and his life is in danger.
I said you should leave town for
a few days, I will help you.
He agreed.
He said I just need to
meet my mother once.
And then...
I... I hate tears Pushpa.
Where are you going?
Do you have an idea?
Yes...
I have a mother.
Hey soldier, it's just two people.
You want to try fighting them?
Have you lost your mind?
Do you want to die?
What happened?
There are people there.
We need to find
an alternative route.
-It's right here. Let's go.
-Wait. Wait a minute.
What?
Did you call him?
Great, so now we are
working with the blackmailer?
And who is he?
This is Bhombol.
So you're here.
Did you come alone?
But sir you forgot to give me the order
of bringing the battalion with me.
-I have this with me.
-Okay, okay.
We cannot put Pankaj's family
in any more danger. Please leave.
Helping Pankaj's family cross
the border is your responsibility.
You have to give them a
home and a new identity.
Deal?
Come here.
What is wrong with you?
Creating a new mess?
Your job was to catch the blackmailer.
Which you did. That's finished--
My job is not to
catch the blackmailer,
my job is to catch the criminal. And those
three MLA's are the criminals. Not Iraboty.
You can decide
whose side you are on.
-You're making a mistake again--
-I am not making any mistake.
I am going.
And if anything happens to me...
then you will have to inform mom.
Aunty... Um... Mausi...
Vasudha ji!
Did Pankaj meet you
before he passed away?
I mean... what did he say exactly?
He said...
"Ma, I will be leaving
for a few days.
Make sure to have
your medicine on time.
Help Trisha prepare
for her UPSC exam."
His books are still here
and he said, "Those would
help her in her studies."
In her studies...
My son...
-Trisha? Trisha?
-Yes.
Are these all the books?
They are not enough.
Are there any more books?
Yes, there are more books inside.
Really? There are more?
Can I see them?
Encyclopedia Britannica.
It's very useful for UPSC.
What subjects are you studying?
Public administration and
Public affairs.
Edition 15 and volume 17.
Easy marks.
Volume 17...
Now we just need to get
them out of here safely.
Something is missing, right?
What?
Lipstick, should I ask Ira?
Do you think this is
'Jaane Bhi Do Yaaron's climax?
'Jaane Bhi Do Yaaron'?
You are still young...
Hey look at that!
Stop them!
Okay?
Take a left from here.
But this is a jungle
what are you saying?
Shekhar take a left, listen to me.
-Here!
-Don't touch the steering!
What are you doing Iraboty?
Shit!
Stop here Shekhar!
-Stop!
-No, we can't stop here.
What are you doing Iraboty?
Have you lost your mind?
What are you doing?
This is sui... sui...
For you.
Thank you.
Will we see each other soon?
I doubt it.
Are you sure?
HEAVY ALLEGATIONS AGAINST STATE
GOVERNMENT MLAs, ARRESTED FOR MASSACRE